Finding Aid for Carl Eugen Guthe Papers
Bentley Historical Library
Carl Eugen Guthe Papers
1905-1974
1920-1929
Bentley Historical Library
Guthe, Carl E. (Carl Eugen), 1893-1974
851379 Aa 2
7 linear feet
The Carl E. Guthe collection contains the papers and photographs of a noted professor of anthropology and director of the Museum of Anthropology and University Museum of the University of Michigan, primarily concerning expedition to the Philippines, 1923-1925.
The papers were acquired in two accessions. The first was transferred by Carl E. Guthe (donor no. 1500 ) in 1944. The second was transferred by the University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology (donor no. 9273 ) in 2003.
The collection is open for research.
Carl Eugen Guthe was born in Kearney, Nebraska, on June 1, 1893. When his father, Karl, accepted a faculty position in the Department of Physics at the University of Michigan later that year, Guthe's family moved to Ann Arbor, Michigan, where he grew up. Guthe received his bachelor's degree from the University of Michigan in 1914. He received two degrees in anthropology from Harvard University, an M.A. in 1915 and a Ph.D. in 1917.
As a graduate student and after receiving his degrees Guthe participated in archaeological fieldwork in Pecos and Guatemala. In 1922 he was hired by the University of Michigan to lead an expedition to the Philippines to locate Chinese porcelains and bring them back for the university's collections. Guthe accepted the position with the condition that the university establish a Museum of Anthropology within the University Museums to house the collections. His condition was met, and Guthe was named the associate director of the museum that same year. He was named director of the Museum of Anthropology in 1929, and given the additional title of director of the University Museums in 1936.
Guthe was instrumental in the development of both museum and academic programs in anthropology at the university. As a museum administrator, he oversaw the development and expansion of the Museum of Anthropology in its formative years, including the establishment of the Ceramic Repository for the Eastern United States and the Ethnobotanical Laboratory. As a faculty member, he founded the Department of Anthropology with Julian Steward in 1929, and taught some of the first formal courses in anthropology and archaeology at the university. He also developed and organized the first courses in museum science in 1938.
Guthe was an influential force outside the University of Michigan as well. He was the principal founder of the Society for American Archaeology, and wrote the original constitution and bylaws. He also served as the organization's first secretary-treasurer, from 1935 to 1940, and as its president from 1945 to 1946. He was chairman of the Division of Psychology and Anthropology of the National Research Council from 1938 to 1941. He held leadership positions in a number of professional organizations, including terms as president of the Central States Branch of the American Anthropological Association from 1928 to 1929, and as president of the Michigan Academy of Science, Arts and Letters from 1939 to 1940.
Guthe left the University of Michigan in 1944 to become director of the New York State Museum and State Science Service. He held that position until his retirement in 1953. After his retirement, he served as a research associate for the American Association of Museums, for whom he conducted a national survey of museums.
Guthe and his wife, Grace, had three sons, Karl, Alfred (also an anthropologist), and James. Guthe died in Knoxville, Tennessee on July 24, 1974.
(For additional biographical information on Carl E. Guthe, see "Carl Eugen Guthe: 1893-1974" by James B. Griffin and Volney H. Jones, published in American Antiquity in 1976.)
The collection, which was received in two accessions, contains papers and photographs documenting Guthe's work at the University of Michigan, including the 1922 expedition to the Philippines and other expeditions and materials relating to his teaching and administrative activities. The collection is organized into eight series: Philippine Expedition Papers, University Files, Philippine Expediting Photographs, Journals, Writings, Clippings, Other, and Correspondence. The 1944 accession includes the series Philippine Expedition Papers, University Files, Philippine Expedition Photographs, and Correspondence. The 2006 addition includes the series Journals, Correspondence, Writings, Clippings, Other, and Photographs..
Archaeology.; Anthropology.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Archaeology.; Expeditions and surveys.; Kentucky.; Ohio.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Ships.; Photographs.; Journals.; University of Michigan -- Anniversaries, etc.; University of Michigan -- Archaeological expeditions.; University of Michigan. Centennial Celebration Committee on University Exhibits.; University of Michigan. Committee on Educational Policies.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Anthropology.; University of Michigan -- Faculty.; University of Michigan. Institute for Human Adjustment.; University of Michigan. Institute of Archaeological Research.; University of Michigan. Linguistic Institute.; University of Michigan. Museum of Anthropology.; University of Michigan. Museums.; Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), 1858-; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Worcester, Dean C. (Dean Conant), 1866-1924.; University of Michigan Philippine Expedition (1922-1925); University of Michigan -- Scientific expeditions.; Guthe, Carl E. (Carl Eugen), 1893-1974.
- Philippine Expedition Papers
  The Philippine Expedition series, 1922-1926 (1.5 linear feet), includes correspondence with Dean C. Worcester, Alexander G. Ruthven, and Francis W. Kelsey, general correspondence, field reports, expense records, and Guthe and Worcester's research notes taken during the expedition.
  - Correspondence with Dean C. Worcester, 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Alexander G. Ruthven
    - 1922-1923 (Box 1)
    - 1924-1925 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Francis W. Kelsey, 1922-1925 (Box 1)
  - General correspondence
    - 1922 (Box 1)
    - January-March 1923 (Box 1)
    - April-June 1923 (Box 1)
    - July-December 1923 (Box 1)
    - January-March 1924 (Box 1)
    - April-June 1924 (Box 1)
    - July-August 1924 (Box 1)
    - September-December 1924 (Box 1)
    - January-March 1925 (Box 1)
    - April-December 1925 (Box 1)
  - First Annual Field Report, 1922-1923 (Box 1)
  - Second Annual Field Report, 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - Third Annual Field Report, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
  - Philippine Refining Corporation
    - Accounts
      - October 1922-January 1923 (Box 1)
      - February-July 1923 (Box 1)
      - August-December 1923 (Box 1)
      - January-April 1924 (Box 1)
      - May-August 1924 (Box 1)
      - September-December 1924 (Box 1)
      - January-May 1925 (Box 1)
  - Expense records
    - 1922-March 1923 (Box 1)
    - April 1923-December 1926 (Box 1)
  - Accounts aboard the "Anne Day"
    - November 1922-February 1923 (Box 1)
    - March-June 1923 (Box 1)
    - July-September 1923 (Box 1)
    - October-December 1923 (Box 1)
    - January-May 1924 (Box 1)
    - June-December 1924 (Box 1)
    - 1925 (Box 1)
  - History of the "Anne Day" (Box 1)
  - Notes on expedition taken by Worcester and Guthe, 1919-1923; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Philippine burial grounds (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Business correspondence and accounts
    - 1922 (Box 1)
    - 1923 (Box 1)
    - 1924 (Box 1)
    - 1925 (Box 1)
  - Questionnaire concerning Pagan tribes of Mindanao (Box 2)
  - Pottery field notes (Box 2)
  - Clippings (Box 2)
  - Account book of Anne W. Day, 1923-1924 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, account books, notebooks, 1 folder (Box 2)
- University Files, 1923-1942
  The University Files series, 1923-1942 (0.5 linear feet), includes papers relating to Guthe's activities at the university, particularly the Institute of Archaeological Research, the Committee on Human Adjustment, the Centennial Celebration Committee on University Exhibits, the Linguistic Institute, and the Committee on Educational Policies.
  - Centennial Celebration Committee on University Exhibits, 1936-1937; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Committee on American Culture, 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Educational Policies, 1938-1942 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Human Adjustment, 1936-1937; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Committee on the Division of Health Sciences, 1936-1938 (Box 2)
  - Delta Tau Delta, 1923-1925 (Box 2)
  - Institute of Archaeological Research, 1936-1941 (Box 2)
  - Institute of Public and Social Administration (formerly Health and Social Sciences)
    - General, 1935-1936 (Box 2)
    - Minutes and Reports, 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Library Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Linguistic Institute, 1936-1939 (Box 2)
- Philippine Expediton Photographs
  The Photographs series, 1922-1927 (0.5 linear feet), includes visual documentation of the landscape, people, customs and artifacts researched during the Philippine expedition. In 1978, prints were made of the photographs before the deteriorating nitrate negatives were destroyed. The photographs are listed by subject in a supplement to the contents list.
  The series also contains photographs of two archaeological excavations in Kentucky and Ohio in 1927.
  - Philippine expedition, 1922-1925
    - "Anne W. Day" and launch (Box 3)
    - Caves (Box 3)
    - Cebu-Opou (Box 3)
    - Graves (Box 3)
    - Landscapes (Box 3)
    - Natural History (Box 3)
    - Moro Houses (Box 3)
    - Moro People and Dress (Box 3)
    - Moro Towns (Box 3)
    - Moro Utensils (Box 3)
    - Pagan Houses (Box 3)
    - Pagan People and Dress (Box 3)
    - Pagan Towns (Box 3)
    - Pagan Utensils (Box 3)
    - Pottery (Box 3)
    - Sacul Island (Box 3)
    - Seashore and Seacliffs (Box 3)
    - Specimens, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Visaya People and Dress (Box 3)
    - Visaya Towns (Box 3)
    - Visaya Utensils (Box 3)
    - Visaya Villages (Box 3)
    - Album 1
      - Yellow and green jar, Siay River, Sebugay Gulf, [1-1] (Box 3)
      - Carved bow of vinta, Siav River, Sepugay Gulf, [1-2] (Box 3)
      - Mt. Apo - very faint, Davao Gulf, [1-3] (Box 3)
      - Barrio on Lower Libuganun R.-Davao, [1-4] (Box 3)
      - Shrine to spirits-Esperanza -Davao, [1-5] (Box 3)
      - House steps pushed out-Manikú-Davao, [1-6] (Box 3)
      - Barracks-Camp Victa, Mabantao-Davao, [1-7] (Box 3)
      - Tall Trees at Camp Victa-Davao, [1-8] (Box 3)
      - Crossing creek just out of Mabantao-Davao, [1-9] (Box 3)
      - Street scene-Barrio Sagayan-Davao, [1-10] (Box 3)
      - Cargadores at Sagayan-Davao, [1-11] (Box 3)
      - Mushroom near Buan-Davao, [1-12] (Box 3)
      - Mushroom at Buan-Davao, [1-13] (Box 3)
      - Buan houses with latrines-Davao, [1-14] (Box 3)
      - On the trail, Buan to Camansa-Davao, [1-15] (Box 3)
      - Giant Abacá; Buan to Camansa-Davao, [1-16] (Box 3)
      - The Sang River Buan to Camansa-Davao, [1-17] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) The barrio of Camansa-Davao, [1-18] (Box 3)
      - Crossing Saug above Camansa-Davao, [1-19] (Box 3)
      - Tree house on Saug above Camansa-Davao, [1-20] (Box 3)
      - Scene along Husgo Creek-Davao, [1-21] (Box 3)
      - Two Dibabaon women, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-22] (Box 3)
      - Crossing the Agusan near Minicayo-Davao, [1-23] (Box 3)
      - The Pines at Minicayo-Davao, [1-24] (Box 3)
      - The red pepper bush at Minicayo-Davao, [1-25] (Box 3)
      - Dibabaon girl Minicayo-Davao, [1-26]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Bagani Lino, Minicayo-Davao, [1-27]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Bagani Lino's wife, Minicayo-Davao, [1-28]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Bagani Lino and his wife, Minicayo-Davao, [1-29] (Box 3)
      - Bagani Lino's new house,Minicayo-Davao, [1-30] (Box 3)
      - Debabaon grave, Minicayo-Davao, [1-31] (Box 3)
      - Crossing Manat River on raft-Davao, [1-32] (Box 3)
      - Roof frame, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-33] (Box 3)
      - Thatch detail, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-34] (Box 3)
      - Typical Dibabaon house, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-35] (Box 3)
      - House with bamboo thatch, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-36] (Box 3)
      - Rest house, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-37] (Box 3)
      - General view-part of Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-38] (Box 3)
      - The forest around Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-39]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Two Toog Trees and Schoolhouse, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-40] (Box 3)
      - Waterfall on Husgo Creek, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-41] (Box 3)
      - Scenes along Husgo Creek, Bauguerohan-Davao, [1-42]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Carved roof pieces, Buan-Davao, [1-44] (Box 3)
      - Typical mountain house, Buan-Davao, [1-43] (Box 3)
      - The Cargadores, Buan-Davao, [1-45] (Box 3)
      - Crossing the Saug near Macgurn (?), [1-46] (Box 3)
      - Barrio of Macgurn. from hill-Davao, [1-47] (Box 3)
      - Pink pinapple [sic]-like flower-Davao, [1-48] (Box 3)
      - Mandaya bolos and scabbards-Davao, [1-49]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Campilan tree with fruit-Davao, [1-50] (Box 3)
      - A new clearing stacked to burn-Davao, [1-51]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Big tree with buttress roots-Davao, [1-52] (Box 3)
      - Peaked roof, Cabanagoy-Davao, [1-53] (Box 3)
      - House along Saug River-Davao, [1-54] (Box 3)
      - Driftwood on Saug River-Davao, [1-55] (Box 3)
      - Auto ferry at Davao-Davao, [1-56] (Box 3)
      - Bagabos near Davao-Davao, [1-57]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Bagobo knapsack-Davao, [1-58] (Box 3)
      - Bagobo portrait (blue tatoo)-Davao, [1-59] (Box 3)
      - Detail of Bagobo coat-Davao, [1-60]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Seven coconut trees from one nut-Davao [detail], [1-61]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Dory at beach, Samal Is.-Davao, [1-62] (Box 3)
      - "Caves" on Malipano Isl., Samal-Davao, [1-63]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Mt. Cipo and the Davao pier-Davao, [1-64]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Panorama of Mati-Davao, [1-65]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Earthquake fault, Mati - Davao, [1-66]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Earthquake tipped house, Mati - Davao, [1-67] (Box 3)
      - Town of Carage, Mati - Davao, [1-68] (Box 3)
      - Burial cave near Manuregao, - Davao, [1-69] (Box 3)
      - Bones in Manuregao Cave - Davao, [1-70] (Box 3)
      - Coffin qmd, Manuregao Cave - Davao, [1-71] (Box 3)
      - Loghry's house, Lianga, Luragao, [1-72] (Box 3)
      - River mouth, Lianga, - Luragao, [1-73] (Box 3)
      - Fruit bats, Lianga bay - Luragao, [1-74] (Box 3)
      - Suyman's house, Loay Bohol, [1-75] (Box 3)
      - Lyman's back yard - Loay Bohol, [1-76] (Box 3)
      - CEG after a morning of cave digging, [1-77] (Box 3)
      - Borotos - Barrio Taying, Loay, Bohol, [1-78] (Box 3)
      - Palms and surf - Tayung, Loay, Bohol, [1-79] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - The beach - Tayung, Loay, Bohol, [1-80] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - The surf - Tayung, Loay, Bohol, [1-81] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Panorama of Rouiblon town, [1-82] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Old Spanish fort and background - Rouiblon, [1-83] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Old Spanish fort - turret - Rouiblon, [1-84] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Old Spanish fort - front - Rouiblon, [1-85] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Sea cliffs - Southwestern Rouiblon, [1-86] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - AND anchored at Sogod, Tablas, [1-87] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable C- on beach at Sogod, Tablas, [1-88] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Pile of fish nets new Sogod, Tablas, [1-89] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Lizard coffin (C- ) - Tablas, [1-90] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - On the cliff face, Pocanil - Tablas, [1-91] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - The cave (C- ), Pocanil - Tablas, [1-92] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Capitan cillo light, Cibu, [1-93] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) - Scene in Petit Barracks, Zacubo, [1-94] (Box 3)
      - Corner of Fort Pilar, barracks, Zacubo, [1-95] (Box 3)
      - Shrine at Fort Pilar, barracks, Zacubo, [1-96]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Model Moro house, Ricodo, Zacubo, [1-97] (Box 3)
      - Landscape near Boloug, Zacubo, [1-98] (Box 3)
      - Zamboauga Constabulary launch, [1-99] (Box 3)
      - First stone mound- Sacul, Island, [1-100] (Box 3)
    - Album 2
      - (unprintable), [2-1 to 21] (Box 3)
      - Road in front of houses- Philveco, [Nov. 1922 2-22] (Box 3)
      - The Day's backyard - Philveco, Cepon, [Nov. 1922 2-23] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable), [2-24 to 37] (Box 3)
      - The rear walk, Opou, [2-38] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable), [2-39] (Box 3)
      - The "Opou" at residence pier, Opou 4.5, [2-40] (Box 3)
      - A sightseeing crowd - Cabungaau, Lauiar, [2-41] (Box 3)
      - The big airplant on board, [2-42] (Box 3)
      - Banca in Black Rock Pass (trip no. 7), [2-43] (Box 3)
      - Sailing Bauca near Cebu (trip no. 7), [2-44] (Box 3)
      - Robertson and his fish (trip no. 6), [2-45] (Box 3)
      - AWD starting on fishing trip, [2-46] (Box 3)
      - AWD starting on fishing trip, [2-47] (Box 3)
      - AWD starting on fishing trip, [2-48] (Box 3)
      - AWD with a bone in her teeth (trip no. 7), [2-49]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - AWD with a list on (trip no. 7), [2-50] (Box 3)
      - The dory volplawning (trip no. 7), [2-51]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - The two dories being towed (trip no. 5), [2-52] (Box 3)
      - The towed dory from the main mast (trip no. 7), [2-53] (Box 3)
      - Lifting dory at Cataiugau, Masbate, [2-54] (Box 3)
      - Lifting dory at Cataiugau, Masbate, [2-55] (Box 3)
      - The Atlas towing the sunken Ajax, [2-56] (Box 3)
      - Empty oil tins in Cebu Harbor, [2-57] (Box 3)
      - Native bauca -, [2-58] (Box 3)
      - Native bauca - detail, [2-59] (Box 3)
      - Native bauca - detail, [2-60] (Box 3)
      - Philveco Mill Opon from S.W., [2-61] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable) Philveco Mill Opon from N, [2-62] (Box 3)
      - Residence gate - Philveco Mill, [2-63] (Box 3)
      - The "Mactan" at the mill dock, [2-64] (Box 3)
      - The launch landing at Cebu dock, [2-65] (Box 3)
      - Cebu dock front and gov. building, [2-66] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable), [2-67 to 73] (Box 3)
      - Gathering firewood for AWD, [2-74] (Box 3)
      - AWD with all sails pulling, [2-75] (Box 3)
      - AWD under sail (foresail down), [2-76] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable), [2-77 to 80] (Box 3)
      - AWD under full sail at Gato, [2-81]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Gato island Oct. 3, 1923, [2-82] (Box 3)
      - WEK on AWD Oct. 1923, [2-83] (Box 3)
      - WEK and "Chief" on AWD - Oct. 1923, [2-84] (Box 3)
      - The Warner Collection packed, [2-85] (Box 3)
      - View from AWD at Bagino anchorage, [2-86]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - View of AWD at Bagino anchorage, [2-87]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - View of Gaas inlet, Dinagat, [2-88] (Box 3)
      - View of Gaas inlet, Dinagat, [2-89] (Box 3)
      - Philveco plant and residences from water, [2-90] (Box 3)
      - (unprintable), [2-91 to 100] (Box 3)
    - Album 3
      - Cattle on Heath's ranch. Masbati, [3-1] (Box 3)
      - Caraboa and cart - Heath's ranch - Masbati, [3-2] (Box 3)
      - The cave at Heath's ranch C-41, [3-3] (Box 3)
      - Hauling logs near Usou - Masbati, [3-4]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Native jar in cave near Usou, [3-5]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Cave near Usou - Masbati - C-50, [3-6] (Box 3)
      - Larens, (Siguijor) harbor from hilltop, [3-7] (Box 3)
      - Bandstand - Basak (Siguijor), [3-8] (Box 3)
      - A rest at Basak, [3-9] (Box 3)
      - The big valley above Maria Siguijor, [3-10] (Box 3)
      - A V-shaped valley in Siguijor hills, [3-11] (Box 3)
      - Walking along Siguijor skyline, [3-12] (Box 3)
      - A picturesque vista - Siguijor, [3-13] (Box 3)
      - A Siguijor sugar mill, [3-14]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - The jar of G-96 Siguijor, [3-15] (Box 3)
      - The site of G-100 Siguijor, [3-16] (Box 3)
      - A possible cache location Siguijor, [3-17] (Box 3)
      - Before digging G-101 Siguijor, [3-18] (Box 3)
      - After digging G-101 Siguijor, [3-19] (Box 3)
      - B-1 (Tabow, Nigros) Oct. 1923, [3-20] (Box 3)
      - Community plowing Bautayau, [3-21] (Box 3)
      - The village well Bautayau Isl., [3-22] (Box 3)
      - A native plow - Bautayau Isl., [3-23] (Box 3)
      - A guide in fishing clothes - Bautayau Isl., [3-24] (Box 3)
      - The guide's house - Bautayau Isl., [3-25] (Box 3)
      - The Cave (c-54) on Jinataugan Isl., [3-26] (Box 3)
      - Boards from nearby wreck. Jinataugan Isl., [3-27] (Box 3)
      - Church at Ubay - Bohol, [3-28] (Box 3)
      - Cave interior - Popog, Bohol, [3-29] (Box 3)
      - Cave interior - Popog, Bohol, [3-30] (Box 3)
      - Cave interior - Popog, Bohol, [3-31] (Box 3)
      - Loading coffins - Popog, Bohol, [3-32] (Box 3)
      - On the southern Bohol road, [3-33] (Box 3)
      - On the southern Bohol road, [3-34] (Box 3)
      - Harvesting rice southern Bohol, [3-35] (Box 3)
      - Site of Sucgang Cave (c.) - Bohol, [3-36] (Box 3)
      - Road building near Caudijay - Bohol, [3-37] (Box 3)
      - Two jars at Cogton, Bohol, [3-38] (Box 3)
      - The green jar Cogton, Bohol, [3-39] (Box 3)
      - The blue and white jar Cogton, Bohol, [3-40] (Box 3)
      - The chauffeur's house, Caudijay, Bohol, [3-41] (Box 3)
      - In the hills near Caudijay, Bohol, [3-42] (Box 3)
      - Site of Inaghoban Cave - Bohol (c- ), [3-43] (Box 3)
      - Mouth of Inaghoban Cave - Bohol, [3-44] (Box 3)
      - Interior of Inaghoban Cave - Bohol, [3-45] (Box 3)
      - Site of Paulangagan, Cautilan Surigao, [3-46] (Box 3)
      - Mouth of Paulangagan, Cautilan Surigao, [3-47] (Box 3)
      - Carabao, and calf in river, Cautilan Surigao, [3-48] (Box 3)
      - Herd of Carabao, in river, Cautilan Surigao, [3-49] (Box 3)
      - Crude bridge near Cautilan Surigao, [3-50]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Church at Santa Fe, Surigao, [3-51] (Box 3)
      - Site of Ilihan (c- ), Cautilan Surigao, [3-52] (Box 3)
      - Site of Ilihan (c- ), Cautilan Surigao, [3-53] (Box 3)
      - The boys swimming to Tilian cave, [3-54] (Box 3)
      - Mouth of Ilihan cave, [3-55] (Box 3)
      - Fish trap at Dinago, Plaur Lurigao, [3-56] (Box 3)
      - Buyungan cave Mainit rodd (c- ), [3-57] (Box 3)
      - Buyungan cave Mainit rodd (c- ), [3-58] (Box 3)
      - Transportation on Lake Mainit, Surigao, [3-59] (Box 3)
      - The cliffs, Lake Mainit, Surigao, [3-60] (Box 3)
      - Paulangagan, Kabatuan, Mainit (c- ), [3-61] (Box 3)
      - Wading near Silop, Surigao, [3-62] (Box 3)
      - Interior of cave near Silop, Surigao, [3-63] (Box 3)
      - The hilltop Ilihan near Silop, [3-64] (Box 3)
      - View of highway from Ilihan, Silop, [3-65] (Box 3)
      - The rocks near Libuag, Hikdop Isl., [3-66] (Box 3)
      - Fishtrap in river near Surigao town, [3-67] (Box 3)
      - Building bridge near Surigao, town, [3-68] (Box 3)
      - Plowing with carabao Surigao town, [3-69] (Box 3)
      - Cave mouth - Turjanday Surigao, [3-70] (Box 3)
      - Washing the dog on board - Dec. 1922, [3-71] (Box 3)
      - A rest and a coconut - Calubian - Nov. 1922, [3-72] (Box 3)
      - Gato from Carnassa - Dec. 1922, [3-73] (Box 3)
      - A banca at Carnassa - Dec. 1922, [3-74] (Box 3)
      - The Moro Collection in Dapitan, [3-75]; 2 negatives (Box 3)
      - Fishing with nets - Larena Siguijor, [3-76] (Box 3)
      - AWD in Port Bombonon, Southern Negros, [3-77] (Box 3)
      - The Cocos at Port Bombonon, Southern Negros, [3-78] (Box 3)
      - A costume (?) of Bombonon, Southern Negros, [3-79] (Box 3)
      - Burial Gr. 52 - Siguijor, [3-80] (Box 3)
      - The Overhang before digging c-11, [3-81] (Box 3)
      - The beginning of work c-11, [3-82] (Box 3)
      - Screening - c-11, [3-83] (Box 3)
      - The trench in c-11, [3-84] (Box 3)
      - Trench almost done, [3-85] (Box 3)
      - The broken big jar - c-11 (~ neg), [3-86] (Box 3)